these increased volumes that we are seeing right now in the broader DeFi ecosystem?
The difference between digitalized finances and centralized finance and crypto finance
is that DeFi is a global hub of liquidity. Since the market is very volatile and we see a lot of
price increases, especially in Bitcoin. We had all-time high recently with $25,000
so there are all arbitrage opportunities between all the different markets, so we see huge volumes
also in terms of arbitrage and we see also a lot of institutions also buying Ethereum especially,
buying also Bitcoin, rebalancing between Ethereum and Bitcoin and a lot of this volume
also happening through digitalized finance through DEXUS. But do you believe like,
I would argue that a lot of the trading that's happening in DeFi is completely kind of independent
in a way that everything happening in DeFi. Do you agree or disagree with that?
You're putting there's more convergence between these two worlds.
So these are two different worlds and we have players, bigger traders who are trading just
in decentralized finances and same in the centralized exchanges, but we have always the
arbitrage volumes. So if something moves up in centralized exchanges, it's going to be
automatically arbitrage with decentralized exchanges. So in general, we see volumes growing of decentralized
exchanges compared to years before. I think it's already like 20 percentages of decentralized
exchanges and centralized exchanges is a little bit different than decentralized exchanges since
you have sometimes no fees for specific market makers. They can just trade and create volumes
with not paying any fees on that. In decentralized exchanges, you need to pay fees like units for
pools, charge 30 beats, 30 beats, 35 beats, 5 beats for stable coins, for example. So it's not
possible to create a huge amount of volume just to show something that the token is.
I'm happy to follow up a bit lower than that than 20%. It's more than 5.15, but I see your
point on that side. I just want to mention one thing. So you mentioned recently that
one inch is doing an integration with Coinbase. What is the goal of that integration? And is it
to try to bridge this CFI/DFI bridge if you want? At this weekend, we announced rebranding
in Singapore and talking in 2049. So we came to the idea, okay, let's everything we have built
over the last five, six, six years. Let's unite it in one single place under oneish.com.
And let's address also the business. We launched our one-inch business products.
We offer 13 Web3 APIs since this year. Those institutions are very open for integrating Web3,
and from our point of view, every business will be Web3 company in the next five to 10 years.
So also Coinbase, they cannot afford to stay behind and had to integrate decentralized
exchanges through our aggregator to also offer own customer access to DEXAs.
Recently, from all the DEXAs we see, Hyperliquid has been one. Obviously,
I've been gathering a lot of attention in the crypto, in the crypto world. What do you think
are the drivers or even the reasons behind the success of Hyperliquid and the crazy dominance
that it's had in really a matter of months? I think it's simplicity. So you can easily interact
with Hyperliquid. I won't say that's a fully decentralized thing, so it's layer two controlled
by the team. It's more or less open. What DeFi is a driver.
You believe the lack of KYC, for example, is one of the main reasons behind the success of
not only Hyperliquid, but Brother DeFi as well. I don't think so that KYC is a problem for anyone.
Since everyone needs to cash out and everyone has centralized crypto exchange account or
brokerage account, so everyone has to create KYC. Otherwise, you cannot cash out.
I see a lot of traders, they don't trust centralized exchanges. This is the point. They don't trust
and they don't want to give own funds to the centralized exchange, but we have seen with FTX
that they gamble with the funds. In our decentralized finance world, you don't trust anyone. You just
verify what you are signing, what order you are making. It's going to be also at the execution.
But is that true, though? In the sense that, yes, you're right. I think DeFi is smart contracts,
but recently we've seen incidents after the Bybit hack, for example, where a lot of these
DeXs are actually more centralized than we think. I mean, to Hyperliquid, the example it just gave
is a good one. Whereas with a lot of centralized exchanges now, they're fully regulated. The
proof of reserves are there. There's regulatory oversight. Do you really believe that that's really
the trust element? There's more trust towards DeXs versus centralized exchanges?
Those people who are using DeFi, so we do also introduce with all the bigger guys who are trading
in DeFi. This is the point point. They don't want to give keys access to own assets to someone who
can be hacked. You have seen Bybit, a huge hack, the biggest hack in crypto history.
Yeah. Those people, these are only two percent of cryptocurrency traders, right?
On the DeFi side, we have a protocol risk, which is a different kind of risk. Sure.
We've seen a taxor as well. But you know, like Uniswap is out there for a long time, a balance
around the curve as well, so one inch since six years out there. And we ensure through a program
that the user gets what they expect and not through policies and people who may do mistakes.
Interesting. What is the one question on the US side as well? Obviously, we've seen
obviously complete change in the US in the last year, and especially with the approach towards DeFi.
How do you think that has an impact on the broader DeFi ecosystem? You mentioned Coinbase is entering
DeFi, for example. Do you believe that would have been possible without the relaxation and
embracing of DeFi that we've seen in the new administration in the US?
I don't think so that Coinbase would just open access to the access for our own users if it would
continue or it was before. And it became much easier for DeFi startups to operate in the US,
especially if you look on the Uniswap labs. They introduced interface fees, for example,
charging fees, earning 200,000 west loss every day on that. And they are comfortable to operate
before to broker a deal of license with that.